It's time to make our skiing game look like a skiing game.
And the easiest way to do that is by adding a snow trail to our main character.
So in this lesson, we're going to look at how we can convert these small little squares into a snow
trail effect.
So first things first, let's move over to one of our snow pixel sprites.
Now let's think about what needs to happen.
Basically, we want this gray block to go to our left ski.
Then when it is at the base of our ski, we want it to glide down.
And obviously this wouldn't really work if we just had one as we wouldn't really have a trail.
So just like before, we can take advantage of cloning to create this effect.
And to save us some time, let's go to our tree sprite and then drag this script here that creates clones
into our pixel sprite.
Now for the next part, we can drag in the when I start as a clone block.
And now what we want is for this pixel to go to our left ski so we can first show it as it's currently
hidden, and then we can go to our motions group and drag in this go to block.
And then select our player sprite.
Then what we want to happen is for our pixel to start moving down, to make it look like we are moving
forward.
Now, an easy way to do this is to grab a repeat block and then stick a change Y by block inside.
Here we can change Y by minus five.
And finally we can delete the clone.
So giving that a test.
Well as you can see it's somewhat works.
But because we have a weight block here it's not spawning in fast enough.
So simply we can remove this block and give that another go.
And well that pretty works quite well.
I think you will see that our pixel does spawn into the middle of our character and as you know, we
want it to follow our sky.
So time for a quick mini challenge.
Pause the video now and try to see if you can get our snow pixel to follow the ski instead of the middle
of our sprite.
Pause the video and give that a go.
Well, hopefully you didn't try to overcomplicate this challenge because the solution is actually quite
easy here.
All you need to do is grab a change x by add it below our go to block, and just keep fiddling with
this number until you get something that perfectly aligns to our scheme.
Like this.
And now to get the other ski working, we can just drag both of these scripts over to our sprite other
sprite here, like so, and then just adding this change x by until it matches with our other ski like
so.
And one problem you may also be facing is your snow pixel spawning in front of your ski character.
And here you you have to do is go over to the looks tab, set this block to go back layer and just click
it.
And you don't even need to bring it in.
And there you have it with the most basic sprite and really simple code.
Look at how much better that makes the game.
It now looks like we're actually skiing, and we have a trail that follows behind us.
And that's all for this lesson.
But before I go, I leave you with a quote from a famous programmer, which is a fool admires complexity,
a genius admires simplicity.
So remember, often the most simple code is the best code.